<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>chmod +x singularity.sh</title><link href="http://bt3gl.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://bt3gl.github.io/feeds/mobgodb.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://bt3gl.github.io/</id><updated>2019-05-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>System Designing and End-to-end applications with AWS Lambda functions</title><link href="http://bt3gl.github.io/system-designing-and-end-to-end-applications-with-aws-lambda-functions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2019-05-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mia Steinkirch</name></author><id>tag:bt3gl.github.io,2019-05-02:system-designing-and-end-to-end-applications-with-aws-lambda-functions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cyberpunk" height="270px" src="./cyberpunk/city.jpg" width="390px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_design"&gt;System design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a really interesting open-ended subject in software engineering, and the way you tackle it tends to tell you how much experience you have in the industry. Every time I learn about a new application or service, I try to imagine its design and, mostly, I love to learn that my approach sometimes was completely off :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite projects in my software career was when I had to implement an end-to-end application to perform some manipulations (with &lt;a href="https://ffmpeg.org/"&gt;FFMPEG&lt;/a&gt;) on video clips whenever they were available in some resource (say, from &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/UsingBucket.html"&gt;S3 buckets&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app I wrote was a Python software running in &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/"&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;, which would be triggered by a message from a &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sqs/"&gt;SQS&lt;/a&gt; queue. The lambda function would then retrieve some specific clip, trim and edit it, and then, when ready, it would 1) save it to a destination bucket, 2) add its metadata to a &lt;a href="https://www.mongodb.com/"&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; database, and 3) send a notification to a &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sns/"&gt;SNS&lt;/a&gt; service, so that the front end bit could pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_function"&gt;Lambda functions&lt;/a&gt; are simply awesome because they abstract several layers in your design (e.g. serverless, anonymous) and they are super easy to set up. But I am getting ahead myself, let's go into more details of each individual piece!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design Consideration&lt;/h2&gt;</summary><category term="aws"></category><category term="scalability"></category><category term="queues"></category><category term="lambda"></category><category term="sqs"></category><category term="mobgodb"></category></entry></feed>